Administrative introduction: agenda, readings, and extra credit rules
2.2
Motivation for transistors and transistor-count scaling
2.3
MOS transistors as voltage-controlled switches
2.4
CMOS logic gates and the CMOS inverter
2.5
Construction of NAND, AND, and NOR gates from CMOS transistors
2.6
General CMOS gate structure, invalid states, and latency
2.7
Dynamic power, static power, energy, and total design power
2.8
Common logic gates, Moore’s Law, and semiconductor manufacturing
2.9
Break and optional Moore paper review
2.10
Definition of combinational logic circuits and functional specification
2.11
Boolean algebra axioms, duality, simplification, and De Morgan’s laws
2.12
Canonical sum-of-products form and minterm notation
2.13
Product-of-sums form, maxterms, complements, and conversions
2.14
Combinational blocks and construction of a decoder
2.15
Applications of decoders in memory addressing and instruction decoding
2.16
Definition and implementation of multiplexers
2.17
Using multiplexers as lookup tables in FPGAs
2.18
Decoder-based logic functions and wrap-up
2.19
Student announcement: Start Hack hackathon